# 哈喽 大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone I am Wang Gang
# 今天跟大家分享一个不一样的视频
Today I will share a special video with you
# 就是很多粉丝问我们这几年来用过什么设备
Many fans have been asking us what kind of devices we use
# 拍摄都用些什么
What do we use for video shooting?
# 今天就跟大家分享一下
Today I will share with you about it
# 第一个是我们的手机在17年的时候
The first is a phone I bought in 2017.
# 我买了这个手机当时咬咬牙
It was a difficult decision when I bought the phone
# 换了这个手机来拍图文拍视频
I used it for taking photos and shooting videos.
# 用了几个月
For a few months.
# 然后现在这个手机已经用不了了
It has stopped working.
# 已经坏了
It's broken.
# 然后 第二个是这个
Afterwards, the second one is this
# 微单一个佳能的微单
a Cannon Mirrorless Camera
# 其实在它前面还有一个
Actually, there's another one before it
# 索尼的家用DV
A Sony DV for home use.
# 因为不会用嘛
As I didn't know how to use it
# 当时那个不会用 买来用了几个月 给卖掉了
I couldn't figure out how to use it so I sold it after a few months
# 那个相机的话亏了不少钱
I lost quite a bit of money on that one
# 就是买新的跟卖二手的亏了不少钱
The price depreciated a lot
# 然后
Then
# 在这个前面还有那个M10
There was also an M10
# 有一个也是卖了
One sold
# 然后有一个是送了朋友
One was given away to a friend.
# 这个是M6
This is M6
# M6前面是M10
M10 was before M6
# 这个的话相机很少用了现在
I seldom use this one now.
# 基本上就是等于现在是一个摆设
It's basically an ornament now.
# 很少用它
I seldom touch it.
# 我们
And
# 然后再后面的话就是这个
After the M6 is this one
# 这个索尼的 稍微一点点专业的一个DV的吧
This is a bit more professional DV made by Sony
# 这个用了
We used this one for about..
# 大概用了半年时间
...about 6 months.
# 当时可能有点冲动买了两台
I impulsively bought two
# 第一台
For the first one
# 买成一万多
I bought it for over 10,000 RMB
# 第二台买成9000多还是8000
The second one was around 9,000 or 8,000 RMB
# 具体我忘记了
I don't remember exactly.
# 现在这个的话就是有时候偶尔
I occasionally use it
# 开一下直播什么的 用一下
for live streaming etc
# 现在也可以开机可以看一下
It can still turn on. Let's have a look
# 这个可以翻过来也比较方便
This can be flipped over so it's kind of convenient
# 然后它唯一一个不好的缺点呢就是什么呢
The only downside is
# 色彩
its color performance
# 不是特别好
not very good
# 饱和度不够高
The color saturation is not enough
# 然后还有这个
And this
# 这个叫什么叫go Pro对吧
It is called GoPro right?
# 两台这个相机唯一的好处就是
The only good thing about it is that it's small
# 小巧
Portable
# 然后可以在水里面拍一下
And it's waterproof
# 但是用的场景比较少
But there are very few use cases
# 两台的话
I bought two
# 花了6000块钱左右吧
They cost me around 6000 RMB
# 然后再后面的话就是
Later I got these ones
# 这个也是同样买了两台
I also bought two
# 买这个微单的话
This mirrorless camera
# 微单不贵
Mirrorless cameras are not expensive
# 我第一次见识到了为什么说微单不贵
I finally understood why they said mirrorless cameras are not expensive
# 镜头贵 这个镜头
The costly part is the lenses
# 这个镜头可能要好几千
A lens might cost over a few thousands RMB
# 但是现在拍的这个是GM的大师镜头
The one we are filming with right now is a G Master lens
# 要一万多 24mm—70mm的
It costs over 10,000 RMB. 24-70mm
# 还有就是像这种
We also have this
# 因为刚开始不怎么专业嘛
At the beginning I didn't know much about cameras
# 就是想
I was just hoping to
# 想要提升好多画质然后买了这种
I just wanted to improve image quality so I bought this
# 长焦的
Long-focus lens
# 还有这个135mm的定焦的
and this 135mm fixed-focus lens
# 其实我们拍做菜的话用的比较少
Actually, we don't really use it much for filming cooking videos
# 拍照片比较适合
It's more suitable for photography
# 两个微单加镜头
Two mirrorless cameras plus the lenses
# 可能花了有十来万吧
these probably cost 100,000+ RMB
# 真的十来万
For real
# 嗯 确实对于
And yes
# 画面是提升了不少
they did improve our video quality by a lot
# 但是现在
However,
# 从我们去年开始升级这款相机
we upgraded to this camera last year
# 就是为了拍4K
just to shoot 4k
# 但是4K的话它又面临一个问题
But with 4k we faced another problem
# 帧率不够
Low framerate
# 看视频的时候会拖影会卡
The video lags sometimes
# 然后又换了
Then we changed again
# 最近又换了个这么个玩意儿
Recently we got this
# 这一坨这一坨其实
This one actually
# 在它的领域里面说
in its category
# 贵也不贵
is not super expensive
# 说便宜不便宜
but not cheap either
# 机身的话
The body
# 八九万
80,000 to 90,000 RMB
# 然后配上乱七八糟
Plus the accessories
# 乱七八糟的东西
and all the miscellaneous items
# 十好几万吧
over 100,000 RMB
# 别看这么大一坨
Though it looks pretty big
# 其实它有很多东西
It contains a lot of add-ons
# 没有的话也拍不了我就说这个卡吧
And it won't do much without the add-ons. Let's talk about the memory cards.
# 三张卡
3 cards
# 512个G的卡
512 GB
# 四五千吧一张
4,000 to 5,000 RMB each
# 四五千一张 三张就要一万多
4,000 to 5,000 each, 3 cards cost over 10,000 RMB
# 这个东西特别贵
So this is pretty expensive
# 大家可以看到我们有的镜头是用的这个航拍
You may notice that sometime we have aerial footage
# 航拍的话就是用的这个飞机
We use this drone
# 这飞机多少钱来着
How much is it?
# 加配件两万二左右
22,000 RMB including the accessories
# 但是我们还是买的低配的
In fact, the one we bought was low end
# 就一个炸机险
with just a damage insurance
# 盒子啊那些都是送的
Things like box and some others are free with it
# 不像我兄弟啊
Unlike my buddy
# 我兄弟华农兄弟他们
My buddy Huanong Brothers
# 买这个还买了专用的屏
They also bought a specific screen for it
# 专用的防爆箱
And a specific explosion-proof box
# 多几千 多五六千对吗
That's a few thousands more. 5,000 to 6,000, right?
# 多五六千
5,000 to 6,000
# 但我觉得怎么说呢
However, in my opinion
# 看个人经济情况来吧
It depends on your personal financial situation
# 这个两万多
This cost over 20,000 RMB
# 还有
Besides
# 这种镜头啊
These lenses
# 这个是Tim老师推荐的
This was recommended by Tim
# 包括刚才这个
Including the previous one
# 这个
This
# 这个电影机也是TIM老师推荐的
This film camera was also recommended by Tim
# 镜头的话就相对于来说
Speaking of lenses, comparatively
# 定焦镜头
This fixed-focus lens
# 比索尼的便宜很多
It's much cheaper than Sony
# 然后性价比要高一些
And better cost performance
# 还有这个
And
# 这个录音机
This voice recorder
# 录音机四五千吧
It's around 4,000 to 5,000
# 也是为了这一次可以 提升更好的音质
It's also for a better audio quality
# 然后还有这个什么
Also
# 监视器
Monitor
# 还有这个麦对吧
And this microphone as well
# 这个麦也不便宜一两千一根 好几根
This microphone is not cheap. One costs over 1,000, and we got several
# 这个麦是配微单的还有这个
This microphone is for mirrorless. And this one
# 这个麦是最早的 其实是配这个的
This is the oldest microphone. It's for this one
# 是配这个的
It's for this
# 然后配这个的
And then for this
# 这个多少钱一个
How much is it?
# 300多一个 买了三个
Over 300 for one. We bought three
# 这上面还有日期
There's a date on it
# 是2019年5月18号买的
Bought on 2019/5/18
# 这一根是7月15号买的
This was bought on 7/15
# 这一根应该买的最早
This should be the oldest one
# 你看
Look
# 这个因为炒菜嘛离得太近被火都
This one was too close to the flame when cooking
# 烧了一些
It's a bit burnt
# 其实我们的相机一般
In fact, our cameras
# 像
Like...
# 像这个吧 像这个
Like this one, you know, this one
# 这刚开始的时候拍做菜
When we first started filming cooking videos
# 油烟特别重为什么呢
It got a lot of smoke. Why?
# 它这个角比较广
Because it has a very wide angle
# 一定要离得够近才行
So it has to be placed close enough
# 甚至有时候我一炒菜那个火都能够烧到这个相机
Sometimes when I cooked, the fire could even burn the camera
# 这个相机也是
This camera also
# 也是 怎么说呢
Also, you know
# 经历过磨难过来的
Made through the hardship
# 还有就是一些电脑
And some computers as well
# 电脑其实也
Actually, computers are
# 不算便宜
Not cheap, either
# 我们剪视频也好 然后
We do the video editing and
# 做一些其它一些东西出差
Make some other things, or go for a business trip
# 比如说要笔记本这些也好
Such as these laptops
# 反正买了十几万
They also cost over 100,000
# 到目前为止我们这些所有的
So far, all the devices we have
# 设备所有的装备
All the devices and equipment
# 我昨天算了个总账
I made a summary yesterday
# 总共接近50万
The total is almost 500,000 RMB
# 其实我都不敢相信投资了这么多东西
I cannot believe I have invested so much
# 不算的话
If I didn't calculate, I wouldn't know
# 不知道一算吓一跳
I was shocked when I calculated it
# 还有就是我们
In addition
# 那个叫什么
What's the name of it?
# 小蜜蜂（领夹话筒）对吧
Lavalier (collar microphone), right?
# 那个无线麦包括我现在带的这个
The wireless mic, and also the one I'm using
# 现在带的这个是重新买的
This one was a repurchase
# 小蜜蜂直接丢了一套 直接弄丢了一套也是几千块钱
I actually lost a whole set of lavalier. Wasted a few thousand
# 其它倒没有什么
There's not much other stuff
# 然后主要就是聊一聊这个东西
Then let's talk about this thing
# 为什么要买这个东西
Why we bought this thing
# 是因为我们的视频
It's because, our videos
# 要跟上这个主流
need to catch up with mainstream
# 主流现在是什么
What is the mainstream
# 未来的主流是
The mainstream for the future is
# 4K60帧对吧
4k 60 fps, right?
# 就是
It's like
# 画质比较精细
The image quality is very fine
# 我们买它的 这个点就在哪里呢
What's the point we bought it?
# 就在于它拍的东西可以更好更真实的还原
The point is it can better reproduce what we are filming
# 而不是说我一定要调什么
Instead of I need some advanced adjustments
# 电影的色调啊什么
Like the color tones or what
# 高大上的场景啊
Or some delicate scenes
# 这些我们用不上
We don't use these features
# 其实很多粉丝
Actually
# 最近也在网上骂我们说我们飘了
Many fans have criticized us recently for losing humbleness
# 买这个不实际怎么怎么样
Like buying these unpractical items, or whatever
# 其实你都不知道我们
Actually, you don't even know
# 对它的一个需求嘛
what our true demands are
# 我们是看需求来买东西的现在
We buy thing according to our demands now
# 比较理性
Comparatively rational
# 不像刚开始买了这么一堆东西
It's not like, we bought a lot of stuff at the beginning
# 花几十万不理性
Spending hundreds of thousands irrationally
# 这次一次性投入了
This time we did a one time investment
# 电影机包括后期的电脑镜头
Filming camera, and also computer for post-production, and lenses
# 乱七八糟的差不多20万吧
Everything adds up to around 200,000 RMB
# 我们现在也是比较理性了
Now we are more rational
# 如果你们感兴趣的话可以下一期
If you are interested, in the next episode
# 或者说过段时间聊一聊我们
Or some time later, we can talk about our...
# 这个账号
Our account
# 到目前为止几年的时间
So far, in these few years
# 它的盈利啊 各方面什么的
The earning, or the other aspects
# 如果你们感兴趣的话啊
If you are interested
# 一定要在评论里面打出
Please do say it in a comment
# 感兴趣
"I'm interested"
# 想要想要听听聊聊这些故事的话
If you wanna know about these stories
# 那就点个赞
Then hit the like button
# 然后在评论里面说想要知道就可以了
And then say you wanna know in the comment, and that's it
# 在后面的话会安排一期
We will arrange one episode afterwards
# 聊聊我们整个自媒体的收入跟开支其实
Talking about the earning and cost of our self-media
# 之前网上有人说我什么
Actually, I've heard someone saying things likes
# 年入过亿啊也好
I earn over 100 million a year
# 过千万也好什么
Or over 10 million
# 月入几百万也好啊这些
Or millions per month, or whatever.
# 我们下期好好聊一聊
We will talk about it in the next episode
# 好啦 最后的话给我们现在要即将
Alright. At last, let's give some suggestions
# 踏入这个美食自媒体也好
To those who want to start a food self-media
# 不管你是拍什么自媒体也好
Or whatever self-media
# 也给你一个建议就是
One advice is that
# 买设备千万不要头脑发热
Please be rational when you buy gear
# 不要一下子全部买回来
Do not buy all of them all at once
# 买回来如果用不上的话
If you buy it but never use it
# 你转手卖二手
Then sell it
# 你要亏的特别多
You will lose a lot
# 亏得特别严重
Lose quite much
# 像我们这个已经是经历了三年
For example, we have already gone through 3 years
# 才沉淀了这么多东西出来
That's how we end up with so much stuff
# 我觉得这些都是
I guess these are
# 可以算是古董了吧
May be counted as antiques
# 可以算是古董了
Can be counted as antiques
# 就是给大家一个忠告就是
Just one advice for you guys
# 想要来拍自媒体的话
If you want to be a self-media creator
# 一定要考虑好考虑清楚
You need to think about it thoroughly
# 一定要是那种抱着试一试那种心态来
Start with the mentality of "I'm just trying something new"
# 抱着分享的心态来不要一开始进来
Have the mentality of sharing. Don't start with, say
# 啊 我一进来要挣多少钱
Ah, how much I should earn after I'm in
# 要怎么怎么样
Or whatever
# 然后来做这个事情反而这样子你 做不好事情给自己压力太大
In this way, you might stress out if things don't work well
# 你就抱着玩一玩的心态来就OK了
Just try to have some fun, which should be good enough
# 就像我们包括现在也是一样
That's how we are doing it even at this moment
# 主要是把精力都放在了做菜上面去了
We spend almost all of our effort on cooking
# 然后关于买这些设备还有一点就是
Speaking of gear, one more thing is
# 买东西一定要货比三家
Pay after shopping around
# 最少比三家
Compare at least three sellers
# 因为现在网上或者是说 哪里的话
Because now online shopping, or wherever
# 买这个东西水啊 特别深
Buying things can be quite complicated
# 同样一个机器
For the same machine
# 跟你开价啊多少
They give you a quote
# 20多万
200,000
# 比如说20多万
Say, 200,000
# 但是你找朋友或者是说有渠道的话
However, if you have some relevant friends or relationship
# 拿这个只要十一二万
It might be 110,000 or 120,000 RMB
# 这中间差了很大一部分
That's a big difference
# 所以买东西的话
So if you buy
# 一定要货比三家
Please pay after shopping around
# 就是谨慎一点
Also, be careful
# 就是不要上当受骗了
Do not be scammed
# 虽然这些相机用的时间比较长
Although we have used these cameras for long time
# 但是它都是可以用的
They are still functioning
# 包括这一台
Including this
# M6对吧
M6, right?
# 包括镜头机身一起4000多
Including lens and body, it was over 4,000
# 当然现在是不值什么钱
Surely now it doesn't cost much
# 如果有想做自媒体的朋友
But if you wanna be self media
# 就是如果你不想投入那么多
and don't wanna invest too much
# 可以考虑一下二手的
You may consider a used one
# 因为这些东西完全都是可以用的
Because it's still functioning
# 还有就是像这种摄像机
And speaking of cameras
# 这个可以拍4K对吧
This one shoots 4k videos, right?
# 这个只能拍1080
This is only 1080p
# 然后像这种收音啊
And voice recorders like this
# 这些都是可以用的
They are all usable
# 如果有兴趣的朋友的话可以给我发私信
If anyone is interested, you can PM me
# 你懂得
You know
# 就是反正都是可以用的
Anyway, they are all usable
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里了
OK, that's all for this episode
# 要吃饭了中午了
I'm going to lunch now. It's noon already
# 拜拜
Bye bye